Paul Jackson个人制作此字幕，仅供学习交流，勿为商用。
QQ交流：374556475
希特勒上台。
柏林，1945年。欧洲已经从纳粹的恐怖统治中获得解放。
Berlin 1945. Europe has been freed from the Nazi reign of terror.
红军正进行着最后战役。
The red army is waging its final battles.
苏联上尉约瑟夫.普劳托夫写道：
Captian Josephus.Plautov，a Russian officer
“仇恨如此之深，我们要结束这场战争，
彻底歼灭那些想杀死我们的军队。”
"The hate went so deep, we want to end the war and annihilate that force that wanted to kill us."
一劳永逸地解决掉。
Finish it off，once and for all.
希特勒已时日无多。
Hitler's days are numbered.
他离开地堡为最终一战而做元首之秀。
He leaves his bunker for one final battle chairmanship
就像在这部宣传电影中一样。
as is seen in this propaganda film.
仍有战士或孩子愿意为他战死吗？
Is there still a soldier or a child, willing to die for him？
战争造成大约5000万人死亡。
The war left some fifty million dead.
他们大多为无辜平民。
Most of them innocent civilians.
对于德国妇女，甚至在炮声趋于沉寂后，仍将遭受着苦难。
For the women of Germany, the ordeal would coninue, even after the canon's gone silent.
著作 >
The book - a woman in Berlin
令人深感不安地详细描述了俄国人在1945年对德国妇女的施暴。
is deeply disturbing account of Russians'rape over German women in 1945.
“他们抓住并推倒我。”
They grabbed me and threw me down.
“我躺倒在地，头靠在台阶上。”
I'm lying with my head on the steps.
“我看见其中一个大兵把风， ”
I see one of the soldiers is keeping watch,
“另一个则撕扯掉我的内衣裤，残暴地强暴了我。”
or the other rips my underclothes and brutaly forces himself on me.
“但后来我们说：你身上压个俄国人胜过美国人在你头上。”
But then we say better to have a Russia on your belly than American over your head.
这个德国女人指的是将她所住城市炸成一片废墟的盟军轰炸机。
This German woman was referring to the allied bombers that bombed her city into ruins.
库达姆 柏林最时髦的大街。
The Kurfürstendamm, Berlin's most fashionable avenue.
13年前，它代表了仍受危机折磨的德国。
Thirteen years earlier, the showcase of Germany, an nation still plagued by CRISIS.
一座纪念碑纪念着一次世界大战的百万受害者。
A monument commemorating millions of victims of the first World War.
玛琳.黛德丽在柏林唱着“蓝天使”。
Marlene Dietrich is singing "Blue Angel" in Berlin.
亚历山大广场。
Alexander Platz.
托马斯・曼在菩提树大街的菩提树荫下欣赏着他的诺贝尔文学奖。
Thomas Mann is savouring his noble prize for literature in the shade of linden trees of the avenue of the Linden.
柏林是欧洲的文化重镇，世界上最开放和宽容的城市之一。
Berlin is a major cultural centre of Europe, one of the most open and tolerant cities in the world.
然而到了1933年, 一下子一切都变了。
Then in 1933，all vite changes.
通过恫吓，煽动和利用德国退役军人的痛苦，
Through intimidation，demagoguery and exploiting the bitterness of German veterans,
希特勒和他的武装民兵,
Hitler and his armed militias，
如中锋队般唱着纳粹党歌 《豪斯特.威塞尔之歌》
like the SA with him "the Horst-Wessel-Lied"
夺取了对德国的控制。
seize control of Germany.
纳粹利用了德国左翼的分裂。
The nazi's taken advantage of the factor that the German left is splintered.
甚至看起来希特勒高举着拳头，做着革命式敬礼也是为了讨好他们。
It even seems like that Hitler with his raised fist, revolutionary salute wants to get them on the good side.
德国共产党人听命于莫斯科，视社会民主党为真正的敌人。
German Communists take their orders from Moscow which views the social democrats as the true enemy.
它们之间不可能有任何同盟。
No alliance is possible between them.
就这样，德国共产党最后一次唱起国际歌。
So for last time, Germany Communists sing the "Internationale".
1933年1月30日，希特勒合法登上了权力的宝座。
Hitler comes to power legally at Januray 30th, 1933.
短短数个月，他的独裁政权便已坚如磐石。
Within a few months, his dictatorship is firmly in Place.
他成为了元首。
He becomes the führer / the leader.
他的支持者齐立，反复高喊 “希特勒万岁”。
His supporters rise and chant "Hail Hitler".
然而，并非所有的德国人都完全信服。
However, not all Germans are totally convinced.
因此一次又一次，希特勒灌输着国人超简单的国家主义口号。
So again and again, Hitler hammers home his simplistic nationalism slogans.
我们身前屹立着德意志。
我们心中德意志正在沸腾。
我们身后全德意志正在跟随。
由于他对群众有着非同寻常的说服力，最终赢得了越来越多人的支持。
And he eventually wins more and more people over, for he has a remarkable persuasion over the masses.
但希特勒想要的是什么？
But what does Hilter want?
在他的《我的奋斗》一书中
In his book - > / >
他清楚叙述了他所谓的“使命”。
He clearly states what he calls "his missions".
作为充满怨恨的一战老兵的一员，他的首要使命将是摧毁法国。
Being one of the embittered veterans of the first World War, his first mission will be to destory France
以洗刷1919年凡尔赛条约剥夺德国武装及部分领土所带来的耻辱。
to wipe out the humiliation of The Versailles Treaty in 1919 which strips Germany of its army and part of its territory.
之后他要征服他所谓的生存空间。
Then he wants to conquer what he calls Lebensraum / living space.
德国有8千万人口，两倍于法国。
Germany has a population of eighty million, twice that of France.
他想让德国获得应有的世界大国地位。
He wants to make Germany the world Power it deserves to be.
希特勒是病态的反犹太主义者，
他的任务还包括确立日耳曼雅利安种族的优势。
这种优势正受犹太人的威胁。
A Pathological anti-Semite, Hitler has also taken on the mission of setting the superiority of Germanic-Aryan race, menaced by the jews.
对他来说，一战，德国的战败，通货膨胀，失业这些都应归罪于犹太人。
For him, the jews was the cause of the great war, Germany's defeat, infation and unemployment.
下一场战争将对犹太人宣战。
The next war will be the war on the jews.
他们将被送到第一个集中营达豪。
They would be sent to the Dachau, the first concentration camp.
希特勒将反纳粹人士，共产党员，社会民主党员
以及所有那些反对纳粹独裁政权的人们都关押在那里。
where Hitler locks up the anti-Nazis, the communists, the social democrats and all those who opposed to the Nazi regime.
最后，希特勒视将所有说德语的民族纳入德意志帝国为己命。
Lastly, Hitler takes on the mission of bringing all German-speaking people into a Reichspost.
首先从他的祖国开始。
Beginning with his homeland.
德奥合并。
The Anschluss.
奥地利被吞并而且马上如德国般屈从于同样的恐怖统治之下。
Austria is annexed and majorly submitted to be the same reign of terror as Germany.
最恶名昭彰的集中营亦随之在林茨附近的茂特豪森开始运作。
With the opening of the most Infamous concentration camp at Mauthausen near Linz.
接下来哪个国家将落入他的魔掌？
Which country will be his next victim?
邻国捷克住有德裔居民
Neighbouring Czechoslovakia with a German populaiton
苏台德德裔
the Sudeten Germans.
但这个国家被英法视为独立国家。
But the country is recognized as an independent state by England and France.
战争阴云密布。
The clouds of war gather.
十一小时的和平会议在纳粹老巢慕尼黑举行。
In Munich, temple of Naziism, an eleven-hour peace conference is organized.
一边是越来越可怕的希特勒。
On one side, Adolf Hitler who is becoming more and more frightening
以及他的盟友
意大利独裁者墨索里尼。
and his Ally, Italian dictator, Benito Mussolini.
墨索里尼首创法西斯主义并将其向全意大利人民进行灌输。
Mussolini, the founder of Fascism and indoctrination over the entire nation from the child to the old.
另一边是西方民主国家。它们赢得了一战，但已精疲力竭。
On the other side, the western democracies, victorious but exhausted from the great war.
保守派英国首相张伯伦
Neville Chamberlain the conservative British prime minister
与法国激进的社会党总理达拉第
and radical socialist French premier Edouard Daladier
想要拯救和平。
want to save the peace.
他们最终接受了无法接受的条件。
They end up accepting the unacceptable.
将捷克苏台德省割让给希特勒
They give up the the Czech province of Sudetenland to Hitler
以换取他郑重承诺不再对欧洲提出任何领土要求。
and exchange for his solemn promised to make no more claims on the other European terriroty.
但是希特勒的承诺有何价值？
But what is Hilter's promise worth?
仅仅六个月后，他入侵了捷克斯洛伐克的其他地区。
Just six months later, he invades the rest of Czechoslovakia
并在元帅赫尔曼戈林的陪同下进入布拉格。
and enters Prague accompanied by Marshal Hermann Galin
戈林曾是一战的战斗机飞行员，亦是纳粹党的缔造者之一
Galin, a former first world war fight pilot, one of the founders of Nazi party,
现在成了航空部长
is now the air minister
和一个正在尝试蛊惑捷克孩童的怪物。
and an ogre trying to charm the Czech children.
希特勒不再需要重新联合说德语的人作为借口了
Hitler no longer needs the excuse of reuniting the German-speaking people
强大的捷克工业将为其效力
The powerful Czech industry will be working for him.
他为什么不好好利用它呢？
Why shouldn't he take advantage of it?
盟国对其姑息养奸。
The allies let him get away with it.
苏联是邻国中最后剩下的可以反击希特勒的强权。
The USSR is last major neighbouring POWER left to counter Hilter.
他与法国签署了一份互助条约。
It signed a mutual-assistance treaty with France
苏联
The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics
是苏俄与其卫星国的正式名称。
is a offical name of communist Russia and its Satellite republics.
斯大林的残忍独裁为其在红场上对群众的操纵所掩盖。
Manipulation of masses in red square masks the ironfisted dictatorship of Stalin
他亦将成百万的可怜富人投入古拉格劳动营。
who's also thrown millions of poor riches into the labour camps, the Gulag.
工业化和强制军事化使苏联成为主要强国之一。
Industilaztion and forced militarization made the USSR a major power
虽然害怕共产主义，西方大国仍依赖苏联。
Despite the fear of the communism, the western powers rely on the USSR.
希特勒准备先发制人。
Hitler is going to beat them to the punch.
1939年夏，在他贝希特斯加登的行馆里，与其外交部长 约阿希姆 冯 里宾特洛甫
In the summer of 1939, in his Berchtesgaden Shelley, with his minister resolving affairs, Joachim von Ribbentrop
准备一项阻隔盟国的策略。
he prepares a blocking maneuver.
希特勒曾发誓要消灭共产主义，现在则派遣纳粹分子 冯 里宾特洛甫前往莫斯科
Hitler who swore to destroy the communism sents von Ribbentrop the Nazi to Moscow
去与其最凶恶的敌人签署一份历史性的条约。
to sign history-making treaty with his worst enemy.
当斯大林的外交部长莫洛托夫签署苏德条约时，
When Stalin's foreign affair minister Molotov signs the German-Soviet Pact.
共产党人全为之震惊。
Communists are totally taken aback
就像这些法国党员。
like these French party memebers.
时值1939年八月，法国人民正享受他们的第一次带薪假日。
It's August 1939 and the people in France enjoy their first paid holidays.
这是社会主义人民阵线的主要胜利成果之一。
One of the major victories of socialist popular front.
在这互不侵犯条约之后有着什么样的原因？
What's the reason behind this Non-Aggression Pact.
苏方一直以来的回应是斯大林在争取时间。
The soviet's answered Stalin is playing for time.
以让希特勒和西方大国自相残杀。
letting Hitler and the western powers kill each other off.
也许打算夺取波罗的海各国以及部分波兰的斯大林
perhaps Stalin who intends to grab the Baltic countries and part of Poland
甚至幻想能与希特勒永久分享欧洲。
even has an illusion that he could share Europe with Hitler on the permanent bases.
1936年，美国国会通过中立法案以免再次卷入欧战。
In 1936, the US congress passed a Neutrality act to avoid being dragged into European war once again.
因此，既然美国和俄国不再令其畏惧，
So with nothing to fear either from the United States or from Russia.
希特勒决定洗刷他所谓的凡尔赛条约中最厌恶的恶行
Hitler decides to wipe out what he calls the worst monstrosity of The Versailles Treaty.
但泽走廊。
The Danzig Corridor.
1919年，德国领土被一分为二。
In 1919, German territory was cut into two.
以让给予波兰出海口。
In order to give Poland an access to the sea.
希特勒渴望于1939年9月1日上午5点35分入侵波兰收复但泽。
Hitler desires to launch his invasion of Poland and recover Danzig on the 1st September, 1939 at 5:35 am.
第二次世界大战的第一枪在但泽打响。
The first canon shot of the second world war is fired on Danzig.
希特勒确信英法不会对此有所行动。
Hitler is convinced that the French and British will not take action
然而英法政府立即会晤向他送去最后通牒，
Yet two goverments meet immediately and send him an Ultimatum,
要他停止一切针对波兰的军事行动。
demanding that he holds all military action against Poland.
希特勒宣称我们的敌人是一些虫类。
Hitler declares our enemy is a little worms
而且他又说谁会为但泽而陷入世界大战的泥沼。
And he adds who wants to get bogged down in the world war for Danzig.
1939年9月13日
September 13, 1939
上午11点，大英帝国大使递送宣战通告。
At 11:00 am, the ambassador of the Great Britain in Berlin delivers a declaration of war.
下午5点，法国对德宣战。
At 5:00 pm, France declares war on Germany.
希特勒对此感到难以置信。
Hitler can hardly believe it.
德国将军们发现他们正面临最糟的状况
German generals find themselves facing the worst-case scenarios.
两线作战。
War on two fronts.
但木已成舟。
But the die is the cast.
希特勒出动纳粹德国的武装力量，国防军
Hitler unleashes the Wehrmacht, the armed forces of Nazi Germany
开往波兰。
onto Poland.
以古代骑士之姿进入战场
Entering battle as a Philippa gone age
波兰骑兵突击德国坦克
The Polish cavalry charges the German tanks
而遭到屠杀。
and is slaughtered.
法国，1939年9月3日
巴黎，东站火车站
Paris，the GARE DE I'EST train station
这些人的许多人25年前从同一站台出发。
Many of these men had shipped out from the same platform twenty five years ago.
而当时的气氛与现在的截然不同。
and under totally different atmosphere.
1914年八月，他们士气高昂开向前线。
In August 1914, they marched off to the war with high spirits.
带着鲜花和他们的步枪。
With flowers and their rifles.
这次没有了鲜花
There's no flowers this time
也没有步枪。
and no rifles.
没人想打这场战争。
Nobody wants to fight this war.
四百万人被动员起来。
Four million men are mobilized.
他们中很多人为农夫。
Many of them are farmers.
法国很大程度上仍为一个农业国。
France is still a largely rural country.
他们步行开往德国边境
They head to the German border on foot
他们的长官骑在马背上在他们后面跟着。
with their offices following on the horse back.
军队仍然对马严重依赖。
Armies still rely heavily on horses.
而这些马从全国各地征集而来。
And these're requisitioned throughout the country.
摩托化尚未普及。
Motorization's not capped up.
开这些橡胶轮胎旧式卡车的加斯通.席黑克回忆道
Jastone Schiller, a driver of one of these out-dated trucks with solid Rubber tires recalls
“我们如此缺少装备。”
"There was such a shortage of equipment."
“我们每辆卡车上每两人用一把步枪。”
"We have one rifle for two per truck."
“我有一盒十发子弹，但不许打开。”
"We have one box of ten bullets which we weren't allowed to open."
“这真是可悲的啊。”
"It was pathetic."
“如果我们万事皆备，我们就会进攻。”
"If we had what we needed, we'd assault."
“因为我们和德佬关系一向不好。”
"because we're no great friend with Boche."
“德佬”是前次大战时对德国军人的蔑称。
The Boche was a pejorative term for the German soldiers during the previous war.
他们也被称作 "vert de gris"
They are also called "vert de gris"
法语意思是平原灰
which in French means field grey
那是德军制服的颜色，能让他们隐入周遭环境。
the color of the uniform which enable them to blend in with the surrondings.
但这些士兵究竟是谁？
But just who are these soldiers?
举例来说，这名德国年轻人边行军边唱
Let's take for example one of these young germans. Marching and he sings
“我们的旗帜在前方飘扬。”
"Our flag is waving before us."
“我们的旗帜代表一个新的时代。”
"Our flag is a new age."
“我们的旗帜比死亡还强有力。”
"Our flag is stronger than death."
他名叫奥古斯特.卡根尼克
His name is Auguste Von Kaganick
他写道：“我认为从军是个对的选择。”
He writes, "I thought the military career is a right choice."
“我父母也如此认为。”
"My parents thought so as well."
“父亲会说至少在军队里你仍可畅所欲言。”
"My father would tell me at least there you can still open you mouth and say what you like"
“你不必行那纳粹礼了。”
"You don't have to do that Nazi salute."
1939年9月，卡根尼克仍然在训练成为一位坦克指挥官。
In September 1939, Auguste Von Kaganick is still traing to become a tank commander.
他写道：“我父亲曾是一名将军，他告诉我。”
He writes, "My father who was a general telling me was telling me"
“法国人在边境上有四十个师而我们是十四个。”
"the French have fourty divisions on the border and we have fifteen."
“剩余各部都在波兰。”
All the rest in Poland.
40万人对20万人
Five hundred thousand men against two hundred thousand
人数上是2比1。
Their number's two to one.
宣战四天后，法军于1939年9月7日发动进攻。
French forces attack on Setmeber 7th, 1939, four days after declaring war.
发动进攻是为反映民意表示波兰未被遗弃。
This offensive launched to show the publics opinions that Poland has not been abandoned.
军队前进8公里到达萨尔区。
Advance is eight kilometers into the Saar region.
法军电影部门炫耀着他们战利品。
The French army's cinema department shows off the spoils of the war
自行车。
Bicycles
“如我们所见，这些开心的骑士，他们收回了”
“这些被遗弃在德国的村庄里的自行车。”
对萨尔的进攻就在那停了下来
The Saar offensive stops there
而产生成一系列在约瑟夫.达农的领导下的精英游击队
发动的小规模战斗。
and generates into a series of skirmishe raised by elite commandos, led by the hero Joseph Darnard.
这位英雄被嘉奖为“法兰西第一士兵”。
Who receives the citation of premier soldier of France.
之后，他将是那些狂热地与德国合作的叛国者之一。
Later, he would one of the most rabid collaborates with the Germans.
而最终在战后被处决。
And eventually, he will be executed after war.
法军虽有自己的英雄和数量上的优势
The French army in spite of its heroes and its superiority in numbers
却无如何进一步的行动
takes no further action.
67岁的甘默林将军
General, Maurice Gamelin, sixty-seven years old
是法英同盟陆军总司令。
is the commandering chief of the allied Franco-British land forces.
因为法军人数比英军要多。
for the French outnumber the British
英国人也认为这场战争不会真的开打
who also think this war isn't for real
一切很快就会平息。
and all will be settled soon.
甘默林本人无意再打一场1914年的战争。
Gamelin himself has no desire to refight the war of 1914.
他不惜任何代价也要避免再次血流成河。
He wants to avoid another blood bath at any cost.
他考虑他需要在马其诺防线后安全地守过两年
He considers he needs two years safe behind the Maginot Line
好让法国重新武装起来。
in order to rearm the country.
马其诺防线为前战争部长安德里.马其诺所建
The Maginot Line is a work of former minister of war, André Maginot
这座结构复杂的防御工事
This complex fortifications
愿意是建来一劳永逸的阻止德国
was made to stop the German enemy once and for all
防线花了近十年建造
It took nearly ten years to construct
并整整耗去150万立方米混凝土
and swallowed up half one and a half million Cubic meters of concrete
和15万吨钢铁。
and a hundred and fifty thousand tons of steel.
所有这些炮塔都由迷宫般隧道所连接
All these gun turrets link together by a labyrinth of tunnels
隧道共长达100公里
one hundred kilometers of them
防线自身延伸达720公里
The line itself stretches for seven hundred and twenty kilometers
从瑞士一直到比利时边境。
from the Swiss to the Belgium borders.
马其诺防线终止于阿登森林脚下。
The Maginot Line ends at the foot of the Ardennes forest.
法国军部过去认为德国坦克永远无法穿越如此崎岖的地形。
The French military command thought the German tanks could never cross this extremly rough terrain.
法国没有将防线一路延伸至海边。
The French didn't extend the line all the way to the sea.
因为比利时在宣布中立前为法国的盟友
Because Belgium before the declaration of its neutrality was an ally with France.
而且对此表示反对。
and oppose it.
北部的战线由法国军队和英国远征军来填补
This northern part of the front is mend by the French army and the British expeditionary forces
之后又得到了来自加拿大和其他远离大英帝国的地方的部队的支援。
later reinforced by Canadians and troops from the far from the British Empire.
在英国，那时有一首流行的歌叫“在齐格菲防线洗涤”。
In Britain, a popular song of the day is the "Washing on the Siegfried Line".
“我们要在齐格菲防线晾晒衣服。”
"We're gonna hang out the washing on the Siegfried Line."
“亲爱的妈妈，你有什么脏衣服要洗吗？”
"Have you any dirty washing, mother dear?"
“我们要在齐格菲防线晾晒衣服。”
"We're gonna hang out the washing on the Siegfried Line."
“因为洗衣服的日子到了。”
"Cause the washing day is here."
齐格菲防线是由希特勒建起的加固防线，面对马其诺防线。
The Siegfried Line is the strengthened fortifications constructed by Hitler, facing the Maginot Line.
德国人不会进攻
The Germans don't attack
他们仍然设法避免出现第二条战线。
They still try to avoid the second front.
尽管如此，法国人仍采取了预防措施，
The French neverthless take some precaution,
他们将阿尔萨斯和洛林的民众疏散至西南部的佩里格尔和夏朗德地区。
they evacuate the population of Alsace and Lorraine to the regions of Peiligeer and Charente in the southwest.
斯特拉斯堡，成了一座鬼城
Strasbourg, a ghost town
她被民众所遗弃，变得毫无生气。
abandoned by its poplulation, emptied of its soul.
尤其是那些犹太教堂
Especially that of synagogues
华沙
1939年9月20日
在9月20日，希特勒下令轰炸华沙。
On the twentieth of September, Hitler orders the bombing of Warsaw.
这座城市被德军包围但仍在坚持。
The city is surrounded but still holding out.
元首想要为之胆战心惊的不仅是波兰人
The führer wants to strike terror into the hearts and minds not only of the Pols
也包括法国人和英国人。
but of the French and the British as well.
这是你们将要面临的状况。
This's what is in store for you.
纽约
1939年9月20日
全世界都吓坏了。
The world is horrified.
在纽约，华沙被轰炸的消息登上了时代广场上的灯牌里
In New York, the bombing of Warsaw is up in lights in Times Square
以及各种报纸的头版。
and on the front page of all the newspapers.
美国总统弗兰克林.罗斯福向全国演讲：
Franklin Roosevelt, the president of the Uited States, addresses to the nation
“这个国家仍将是个中立国家”
"This nation will remain a neutral nation "
“但我无法要求每个美国人在思考方面也保持中立。”
"But I cannot ask that every American remain neutral in thought as well"
“甚至中立者也有权考虑事实。”
"Even a neutral has a right to take account of facts"
“甚至中立者也不能被要求封闭他的内心或是他的良知。”
"Even a neutral cannot be asked to close his mind or to close his conscience."
华沙被炸显出这些城市有多脆弱。
The bombing of Warsaw shows how vulnerable the cities are.
巴黎开始着手保护她的名胜古迹。
Paris settles about protecting its monuments
并把博物馆的名作藏至外省。
and hides its museum Masterpieces out into the provinces.
在埃菲尔塔脚下的战神广场
The Champs-de-Mars at the foot of The Eiffel Tower
到处挖有防空避难所
is dug full of bomb shelters
并经常进行防空演习。
and the refrequent aerial drills
防毒面具被强行要求戴上。
Gas masks are compulsory.
毒气在上次大战里被使用，现在所有人都害怕它们。
Poison gases were used in the first world war and now everyone is afraid of them.
甚至马也是。
Even the horse is.
与此同时波兰被无情地瓜分殆尽。
Meanwhile Poland is ruthlessly carved up.
按照之前与希特勒协商好的，苏联军队入侵东部波兰。
As previously agreed with Hitler, the Soviet has invaded the eastern half of Poland.
在这里德苏军人称兄道弟
Here German and Soviet soldiers are fraternizing
真是矛盾的一幕啊。
and incongruous sight to say the least.
纳粹发送传单其中读到：
The Nazi hand out the files to read:
“德国军队向工农红军致敬”
"The German army saluts the red army of workers and farmers, "
“我军一直向你们致以最高的敬意。”
"which we always hailed in the highest respect."
波兰军队投降德国
The Polish Army surrenders to the Germans
而在东面则是向苏联。
and in the east to the Soviet.
斯大林于是下令处决两万波兰战俘。
Stalin then orders the execution of twenty thousand Polish prisoners.
他要消灭这个他正打算吞并的国家的精英。
He wants to eliminate the elite of the country he intends to annex.
俄国斯摩棱斯克附近的卡廷森林里，四千五百波兰军官被枪击头部处决。
Four thousand five hundred Polish officers are executed with a bullet in the head in the Katyn forest near Smolensk in Russia.
两年后，在克里姆林宫斯大林接见波兰流亡政府的首脑
Two years later, at Kremlin Stalin meets with the head of Polish goverment in exile
史科尔斯基将军
General Sikorski
将军递交了一份失踪的波兰军官名单。
who delivers a list of missing Polish officers.
苏联拒绝承认有任何差错。
The Soviets deny any wrong doing.
在1992年，苏联解体后的俄罗斯总统鲍里斯.叶利钦
In 1992, the president of post-Soviet Russia, Boris Yeltsin
将呈给波兰总统瓦文萨
would present Polish president Lech Walesa
一份由斯大林自己签署处决的命令原件。
with an original order of execution signed by Stalin himself.
通过占据半个波兰，斯大林实际上已落入了希特勒的圈套中
Stalin by occupying half of Poland is in fact playing into the hands of Hitler
希特勒需要与苏联的共同边界以便实行侵苏计划。
who need the common border with USSR to facilitate his plans to invade Russia.
希特勒与党卫军首脑希姆莱现在将“好好”照顾一下波兰
Hitler and Himmler, the head of SS, will now take care of Poland
他们任命纳粹党人汉斯.弗兰克为波兰占领省份的总督。
by naming the Nazi Hans Frank Governor General of the occupied Polish provinces
弗兰克宣称:“我握有对所有的波兰人的生杀大权。”
who claims, "I have the power of life and death over the Polish people."
战后，他将在纽伦堡接受审判
After the war, he will be tried in Nuremberg
并以反人类罪被处以绞刑。
and hanged for crimes against humanity.
一位德国人摄下了这些被拘于围栏里的吉普赛人
These gipsies held in pens are filmed by a German
对于纳粹来说，他们已经不是人了。
For the Nazis, they are non persons.
妇女将被强制接受结扎手术
The women will be forced to undergo a Sterilization
因为他们不配有权生儿育女。
because they do not deserve to reproduce.
纳粹宣布公开抓捕吉普赛人。
The Nazis declare open seizing on Gipsies.
数十万人将被关进集中营里。
Hundreds of thousands will be in interned in concentration camps.
犹太人民的苦难开始了
The ordeal over the Jewish people begins
纳粹现在发现已有300万波兰犹太人处于他们的统治下。
The Nazis now have three million Polish Jews at their mercy
希特勒仍不确定如何处置他们
Hitler is still uncertain about what to do with them
只要战争对他来说进展顺利
As long as the war is going well for him,
他考虑把他们流放到东方或是用船把他们运到马达加斯加。
he considers deporting them to the east or even shipping them to Madagascar.
只有当战争结局变得不明朗时
It's only when the outcome of the war becomes less certain
希特勒与其同伙将开始宣泄他们狂乱的仇恨和杀戮
that Hitler and his complices unleash a frenzy of hate and murder
那就是“最终解决方案”
The Final Solution
此时，犹太人都要被辨认出来。
For the time being, the Jews have to be identified,
标上黄星作为标记
marked with a yellow star
并被集中到犹太区内。
and herded into the ghettoes
他们中的一些被完全用墙隔离。
some of which are completely walled off.
其中一位不幸受难者在日记里写道
From the diary of one of these unfortunate souls
“看着眼前可耻的罪行和暴力令人心碎。”
"It's heartrending to see shameful sins and violence take place before our eyes"
“小恶棍们就在外面的大街上殴打妇女和老人”
"Women and the elderly beaten right out in the street by petty thugs"
“我的眼中充满了泪水。”
"Tears come to my eyes"
“我们的无能为力和孤立无援暴露无遗”
"our powerlessness, our isolation is there to see right in open"
“完全没人向我们伸出援手。”
"when not a single person takes us a defense. "
“我们好弱啊。”
"We are so weak."
波兰所有主要城市都将设立犹太人隔离区
All the major cities in Poland will have their ghetto prisons
罗兹犹太区
来自德国，奥地利，捷克的犹太人也将拘押在此。
where German, Austrian and Czech Jews will also be interned.
犹太人在这仍自信也许某一天他们能返回故土。
The Jews here still feel confident that perhaps someday they will be able to return to their homes
他们不知道自己即将因冻饿而死。
They don't know that they will die of hunger and cold.
他们不知道毒气淋浴室的大门即将向他们打开。
They don't know the shower is about to begin.
犹太人居住地
禁止进入
华沙已成废墟。
Warsaw is in ruins.
希特勒来到华沙以让一队宣传工作人员为其拍摄，
Hitler comes to be filmed by the a propaganda crew,
他们乘在移动的轿车上从后方朝着希特勒这边进行拍摄。
seeing here, travelling in the car and the background.
这些胜利的德国士兵随着《近卫军进行曲》踏着正步。
These victorious German soldiers march their Goose step to the song of Grenadiers March
但在波兰战役期间，他们的作战效率过于低下
But they were too inefficient during the Polish campaign
准备不足，缺乏战斗精神，甚至有时开小差
Poor preparation, a lack of fighting spirit, even cases indiscipline
总司令勃劳希契就这样大胆向元首作了汇报。
On the points, the commanding chief, general von Brauchitsch does report to the führer.
沃尔特・冯・勃劳希契
希特勒对此大发雷霆。
Hitler is furious.
但他不为疑虑所影响并下令准备对西面发动进攻。
But he is immune to doubt and orders the attack on the west to be prepared
进攻荷兰，比利时和法国。
And attack Netherlands, Belgium and France.
某些将军这么做是疯狂的。
Some of the generals think it's madness.
其中一些人开始密谋推翻元首。
Some of them begin plotting to overthrow the führer.
这是关键时刻。
This is the crucial moment.
历史进程正处在紧要关头。
The course of history lies in the balance.
1939年11月89日，希特勒惊险逃过暗杀行动。
November 8th, 1939, Hitler narrowly escapes from a assassination attempt.
似乎仿佛他受到了上天的某种保护。
It seems as if he enjoyed some kind of divine protection.
当他参加遇难者的葬礼时
When he attends the funeral for the victims
已经变了一个人。
He's no long the same man.
他对军队和德国人民的影响力甚至变得更大。
His power over the army and the Germany people has grown even stronger.
他告诉他的将军
He tells his generals,
“我的决定不可改变。时机一到我就进攻法国。”
"My decision is revocable. I will attack France when the time is right."
“不成功便成仁。”
"I will be victorious or die in the attempt."
但希特勒对进攻西方仍感到不确定。
Yet Hitler is still uncertain about attacking the west,
因为他也说：
for he also says,
“战争就像打开黑暗房间的门。”
"War is like openning a door of dark room."
“你永远不知道会发生什么事。”
"You'll never know what will happen."
最终，他延迟了进攻命令
Eventually, he postpones the order to attack
回到他在阿尔卑斯的行馆与他的情妇伊娃布劳恩相会。
and goes back to his Shelley in the Alps to join his mistress, Eva Braun.
她拍下了这段希特勒随员的影片。
She shot this footage of Hitler's entourage
帝国建筑师施佩尔
of the Reich's architect, Albert Speer
常和希特勒散很长的步。
who goes for long walks with Hitler.
施佩尔回忆道：
Speer recalls,
“希特勒想把柏林重命名为‘日尔曼尼亚’。”
"Hitler wanted to rechristen Berlin 'Germania'."
“我们已备好未来希特勒广场的模型，
而广场圆顶的灵感来自罗马圣彼得大教堂。”
"We are ready to have mocked up the future Adolf Hitler Square with a dome inspired by San Peters in Rome
“但比它大十七倍。”
but seventeen times bigger.
我对他说：“元首，这不会成为轰炸机的理想目标吗。”
I said to him, "My führer, wouldn't that make a ideal target for bombers."
他答道：“一点也不会。
戈林已向我保证任何一架敌机都无法飞跃帝国领空。”
He answered, "Not at all. Galin has assured me that no enemy aircraft will ever fly over the reich."
未来的德国军官卡根尼克在兵营里写信给母亲：
From his barracks, the future German officer, Auguste Von Kaganick, writes to his mother,
“我们全都渴望战斗。”
"We are all eager to fight."
“我们已做好战争准备。”
"We are ready for battle."
他的母亲回信道：“这是场罪恶的战争。”
His mother answers, "This war is a crime."
“而我们将为之付出代价。”
"And we are going to have to pay for it. "
战争这时进入一个怪诞的阶段
The war then enters a new bizarre phase.
德国人称之为“静坐战争”。
The Germans call it der Sitzkrieg/the sitting war
英国人称之为“虚假战争”。
The British call it the phoney war
而法国人则视之“可笑战争”。
And for the French, it's Drole de guerre/the funny war.
这漫长奇怪的等待时期
A long strange waiting period
对妇女来说尤其艰辛
especially hard on the women
对她们来说不仅要承受战争带来的极大痛苦
For them, there is not only the anguish of the war
还得担忧家人的安危。
but also the survival of their families to worry about.
就像上次大战一样，士兵们挖着战壕并设法充分利用一切。
As in the last war, the soldiers dig in and try to make the best of things.
法国士兵加斯通.席黑克写信给妻子：
The French soldier, Jastone Schiller, writes to his wife,
“气温低至零下30度，面包都冻住了。”
"It's thirty degrees below zero, the bread is frozen."
“我是幸运儿中的一个，他们给了我们些稻草。”
"I'm one of the lucky ones, they gave us some straw."
“有了它，我们能睡得好些。”
"And with that, we can sleep better."
1939到1940年的冬天确实是本世纪最冷的冬天之一
The winter of 1939 and 1940 is indeed one of the coldest in the certury
雪上加霜的是，这场战争的所有冬天都是酷寒的。
to make the bad situation worse, all the winters of this war will be brutally cold.
总司令甘默林期望德国经比利时进攻
The commanding chief, general Gamelin, is expecting Germans to attack through Belgium.
进而穿越这片开阔的平原前往法国。
and move towards Paris acorss this open plain.
就像1914年那次。
Like in 1914.
甘默林计划让法军在比利时的土地上抵抗德国。
Gamelin plans to make it stand agianst Germans on Belgium's soil.
在法国，即将为自己闯出名号的坦克军官戴高乐上校批评这项战略。
In France, colonel de Gaulle, a tank officer who's beginning to make a name for himself criticize this strategy.
他称之为“马其诺防线心态”
He calls it the-maginal-Line mentality
也就是等待另一方采取行动。
which consists in waiting for the other side to make a move.
在他的著作《建立职业军》中
In his book 'Towards a Professional Army'.
他辩证支持大量使用坦克发动进攻
He argues in favour of taking the offensive, making massive use of tanks.
法国月产300辆坦克
France is producing three hundred tanks a month
但它们都被分配到下属各部来支援步兵
But they are being disbursed into all the sections to back up the infantry.
法国的航空工业也落于人后。
French aviation has also fallen behind.
法国从美国订购了四千架飞机
France orders four thousand plants from the United States.
尽管后者国内孤立主义的趋势愈来愈盛。
in spite of the ever-growing isolationist trend
支持孤立主义的查尔斯.林白
championed by Charles Lindbergh
曾是首位单人驾机跨越大西洋的英雄
the hero who made the first transatlantic solo flight
而现在则是美国第一运动的主要倡议者。
and now leading proponent of the America-first movement
“如果你相信美国的命运应是独立的。”
"If you beleive in an independent destiny for America."
“如果你相信本国应远离欧战。”
"If you beleive that this country should not enter the war in Europe."
“我们要求你站在她的立场加入美国第一委员会。”
"We ask you to join the America-First committee in its stand. "
这是美国孤立主义者的声音
It's the isolationist voice of America
也是反犹汽车制造者亨利福特等公众名人的想法
and the public personalities like Henry Ford, the anti-Semitic car-maker
或像当时美国驻伦敦大使约瑟夫.肯尼迪一样主张反战
or like Joseph Kennedy, American ambassador in London who is anti war
而他的儿子，未来的肯尼迪总统则支持欧洲民主国家。
while his son John, the future president Kennedy supports European democracies.
美国的纳粹的支持者们也促成了1940年初充斥社会的狂热氛围
Nazi sympathizers in America also contribute to the impassioned climate that reigns at the beginning of 1940.
在欧洲，英国的法西斯联盟也相当活跃。
In Europe, the British union of Fascists are also quite active.
但后来遭禁。
after the moment they are banned.
英国的“元首”奥斯瓦德.莫斯利公然在伦敦的市中心挑战政府。
Oswald Mosley, the English führer, challenges the goverment right in the centre of London.
之后数年他将呆在监狱里。
He will spend next several years in prison.
莫斯利演讲驱使人们走上街头来停止战争。
Mosley's speeches urge people to get out on the streets and stop the war.
但丘吉尔已掌管英国政府。
But Winston Churchill has taken the reigns of English goverment.
这里我们看到他陪同法国将军甘默林和达尔朗海军上将
Here we see him with the French general Gamelin and admiral Darlan
后者正在伦敦作正式访问。
who are on a official visit to London.
英法组建了一只远征军前去救助芬兰
A Franco-British expeditionary corps is formed to help Finland
后者正受到苏联的侵略。
which is being invaded by Soviet Union.
法国正准备拍出他的精英战士
France is preparing to send its elite soldiers
法国外籍兵团
the French foreign legion
一个世纪来，外籍兵团一直不记前嫌吸纳世界各地的恶棍
The foreign legion, for a century, it's been taking in the world reprobates no matter what they have passed
只要名声不要太臭就行了。
as long as it's not too shitty.
他们驻扎在阿尔及利亚的西迪贝勒阿巴斯 。
They have quarters in Sidi Bel Abbès, in Algeria.
现在签下了许多西班牙共和党人
Now signs of a good number of spanish republicans
这些人在弗朗哥的法西斯胜利后从国家逃了出来
having fled from their country after Franco's Facist victory.
而现在渴望与支持弗朗哥的法西斯作战。
Then now eager to fight the Nazis who support Franco.
他们都将长途跋涉前往法国。
They all make the long trip to France.
兵团与装备精良的阿尔卑斯特种部队一同在布雷斯特登船
The legion has embarked at Brest, along with the well-equipped Chasseurs Alpins
后者是一支受训在雪地作战的山地部队。
a mountain corps, trained for action in snow.
但芬兰和苏联签署了和平协定。
But Finland and the Soviet Union sign a peace treaty.
几天之后，希特勒对丹麦和挪威发动进攻。
A few days later, Hitler launchs his offensive against Denmark and Norway.
闪电战。
The Blitzkrieg/the lightning war
国防军两日内占领奥斯陆。
The Wehrmacht takes Oslo in two days.
希特勒正寻求保护铁矿运输线。
Hitler is seeking to protect the iron routes.
铁对于德国作战是不可或缺的。
Iron is indispensable to the German war effort.
而瑞典铁矿石的一半经由挪威的纳维克港运出。
And fifty percent of the swedish Iron ore is shipped out of the Norwegian port of Narvik.
法英远征军登陆纳维克。
The Franco-British expeditionary corps lands in the field of Narvik.
经一月战斗，盟军拿下了纳维克。
After a month's fighting, the allies take Narvik.
矿路暂时被切断。
The iron route is temporarily cut.
这场胜利提升了法国士气
This victory is good for French morale
并使他们更相信自己的格言。
and adds credence to their motto,
“我们会赢，因为我们是最强的。”
"We'll win, because we are the strongest."
但是远征军将不得不放弃纳维克。
But the expeditionary corps will have to abandon Narvik.
接下来直到战争结束，一车又一车的瑞典铁矿石
And for the rest of the war, trainload after trainload of Swedish iron ore
将一直喂饱德国的战争机器。
will feed the German war machine.
法国人尽数撤回国内，因为德国刚在西线发动了攻势。
The French are broad back home for the Germans just launch their offensive in the west.
1940年5月9日，希特勒乘着他的专列“美国号”离开柏林
The 9th of May 1940, Hitler left Berlin on his private train code-named America
向西驶往位于法国边界附近的新指挥部。
heading west towards new headquarters near the French border.
希特勒宣布：“先生们，进攻才刚开始。”
Hitler announces, "Gentlemen, the offensive has just begun."
他的将军在冬季期间向他呈上了作战计划。
His generals have submitted him the battle plan during the winter
看上去与1914的相类似
It looks similar to that of 1914
经由比利时进攻
Attack through Belgium.
但希特勒偏爱冯曼因施坦将军想法。
But Hitler preferred the general von Manstein's idea
直穿阿登森林
cutting straight through the Ardennes Forest
然后挥师北上直达大海。
then swinging up and driving towards the sea
以“镰割”攻势将盟军包围。
encircling the allies with a sickle-cut movement
但此“镰割”攻势实属一场豪赌。
But this sickle-cut movement is in fact a huge gamble.
因为盟军可能会掉头反击。
Because the allies could turn back and counterattack
然而希特勒却自信满满
However Hitler is confident
他心里明白主要是天气要好。
He knows the main thing is to have a good weather.
1940年5月10日
中尉卡根尼克断言：
lieutenant Auguste Von Kaganick claims,
“我们是国防军，大德国的军队。”
"We are the Wehrmacht, the armed forces of great Germany."
“吾师必胜。”
"Victory is certain."
对于德国军人来说，自己的祖国正处于危险之中。
For the German soldiers, their homeland is in danger.
毕竟是法国向德国宣的战。
After all, it was French who declare war on Germany.
1940年5月10日黎明时分，德国伞兵空降荷兰。
The 10th of May 1940, at dawn the German parachutists make jump over Holand
他们受命夺取鹿特丹周边的机场和桥梁。
Their mission is to capture the airfields and bridges around Rotterdam.
与此同时，希特勒出动大军杀向比利时。
At the same time, Hitler unleash his war machine on Belgium.
希特勒等待着。
Hitler waits.
盟军是否会落入陷阱之中？
Will the allies fall into the trap?